Pennsylvania Adult Education Collection
Pennsylvania Adult Education Collection
1993-2006
1.0 linear ft.
Printed material (conference proceedings, issues of PAACE Journal of Lifelong Learning), most somehow connected with Indiana University of Pennsylvania
## Use our field 001
Biographical History
The Pennsylvania Association for Adult and Continuing Education (PAACE) was created in 1978 as a statewide professional organization which serves as an advocate for adult and continuing education. The membership includes professionals and volunteers from all aspects of adult continuing education, that is adult basic and general education, English as a second language, continuing higher education, literacy education, and workforce development. PAACE is also the publisher of The PAACE Journal of Lifelong Learning, a refereed journal published annually with the sponsorship of Indiana University of Pennsylvania.
The Midwest Research to Practice Conference in Adult, Continuing and Community Education, first held in 1981. is a two day meeting held each fall at a major university in the Midwest United States. This conference provides a forum for practitioners and researchers to discuss practices, concepts, evaluation, and research studies to improve practice in adult education.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Pennsylvania Adult Education Collection contains conference proceedings and journal issues.
Arrangement of the Collection
Alphabetical by type or title, and within that chronological.
Related Material
The library holds a considerable number of collections related to adult and continuing education, which collectively are known as the Alexander Charters Library of Resources for Educators of Adults. Please refer to for a complete listing. Holding also contain numerous publications (books, newsletters, pamphlets, and professional journals); please refer to to locate these items.
Subject and Genre Headings
Adult education; Midwest Research-To-Practice Conference in Adult and Continuing Education.; Pennsylvania Adult and Continuing Education Research Conference.; PAACE journal of lifelong learning.; Adult education -- Research.; Adult education -- United States.; Pennsylvania.; Journals (periodicals); Proceedings.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Trenton R. Ferro and Gary J. Dean, 2008[?]
Inventory
- Conference proceedings
  - Midwest Research-To-Practice Conference in Adult and Continuing Education, 12th, 1993; co-hosted by Indiana University of Pennsylvania (Box 1)
  - Midwest Research-To-Practice Conference in Adult and Continuing Education, 22d, 2003; co-hosted by Indiana University of Pennsylvania (Box 1)
  - Pennsylvania Adult and Continuing Education Research Conference, 1st, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Pennsylvania Adult and Continuing Education Research Conference, 2d, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Pennsylvania Adult and Continuing Education Research Conference, 5th, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Pennsylvania Adult and Continuing Education Research Conference, 6th, 2003 (Box 1)
- Journals
  - PAACE Journal of Lifelong Learning, Vol. 2-Vol. 7, 1993-1998; 6 issues (Box 1)
  - PAACE Journal of Lifelong Learning, Vol. 8-Vol. 15, 1999-2006; 8 issues (Box 2)